《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
我已经戒酒一年了
I've been sober for a year.
这无法抹去我的过错
That doesn't erase the things that I did.
但我还是在乎你的
But I still care about you.
亲爱的吉姆
Dear Jim,
我以为我能为你勇敢坚强起来  可我做不到
I thought I could be strong and brave for you, but I can't.
我会暂时离开  努力振作起来
I'm going away for a while, to get myself together.
你信任我  我就信任你
Trust me, and I'll trust you.
现在  你们每个人的税都要加25%
In the meantime, each of your tariffs will increase 25%
去联系萨维亚诺和图斯基
Reach out to Saviano and Turski.
他们担心自己会落得巴尼恩的下场
They're worried about ending up like Bannion.
老家伙在把他的手下赶到我这边
The old man is herding his sheep toward me.
自大的小丑
Arrogant clown.
想扳倒我
Trying to take me down!
你不知道极限在哪
You do not know where the edge is.
阿卡姆疯人院
Arkham Asylum?
去给疯子做保安
A security guard for nut-jobs?
不是这个就得辞职了
It's that or quit.
那就辞职啊
So quit.
他们就希望我辞职
That's what they want me to do.
法尔科内  市长
Falcone, the mayor,
我不会停手的  哈维
I'm not gonna stop, Harvey.
我会抓到他们所有人
I'm gonna get them.
阿卡姆疯人院
要是你不好好做我吩咐你做的事  或是心中不情愿
[出自莎士比亚话剧《暴风雨》  朱生豪译本]
If thou neglect'st or dost unwillingly what I command,
我要叫你浑身抽搐
I'll rack thee with old cramps.
叫你每个骨节里都痛起来
Fill all thy bones with aches,
叫你在地上打滚咆哮
make thee roar
连野兽听见你的呼号都会吓得发抖
that beasts shall tremble at thy din.
到你了  上
Go, go.
不要
No.
我求求你
Pray thee.
我不得不服从
I must obey.
因为他的法术有很大的力量...
His art is of such power...
很大的力量...
Such power...
"就是我老娘所礼拜的神明"
"It will control my dam's God."
就是我老娘所礼拜的神明塞提柏斯也得听他指挥
It would control my dam's God Setebos
做他的仆人
and make a vassal of him.
贱奴  去吧
So, slave, hence.
去吧
Hence.
五寻的水深处躺着我的父亲*
*Full fathom five my father lies
他的骨骼已化成珊瑚*
*of his bones are coral made,
他眼睛是耀眼的明珠*
*those are pearls that were his eyes
他消失的全身没有一处*
*nothing of him that doth fade
不曾受到海水神奇的变幻*
*but doth suffer a sea change
化成瑰宝  富丽而珍怪*
*into something rich and strange...
退后
Get back!
退回去
Get back.
别杀我
Don't kill me!
趴下
Stay down.
这是你被调派到这里后
This is the fourth inmate outburst
发生的第四起病人暴动了
in as many weeks as you've been stationed here.
我明白这差事对你是处罚
I understand this is punishment duty for you,
但我希望你仍然要有点专业水准
but I expect professional standards nonetheless.
这种错误是不能容忍的  戈登
This is unacceptable, Gordon.
不能容忍
Unacceptable.
是我的错  朗先生
It's my fault, Mr. Lang.
这个剧目的情绪太压抑了
The play was too upsetting.
以后还是演喜剧吧
We'll stick to comedies from now on, I think.
谢谢你  邓肯护士
Thank you, Nurse Duncan.
你可以叫我"院长"或者"朗医生"
It's "Director" or "Dr. Lang," as you prefer.
此次谈话不涉及娱乐活动
Recreational activities are not pertinent to this conversation.
戈登警卫负责本区的安全
Officer Gordon is responsible for security on this wing,
而看来他无法完成这一任务
a task which he seems unable to manage.
你对此有什么要说的  戈登
What have you to say about this, Gordon?
这个人需要医疗救助
This man needs medical attention.
我倒想自己治疗他
I'd see to him myself,
但是医院有规定
but there's rules.
我只负责配药  不能给人治病
I dispense meds, not treatment.
他需要医生
He needs a doctor.
那好吧
Very well.
我去找一个来
I'll send one in.
再发生事故
Any more incidents,
我就安排你去治疗病房轮班
and I'll have you placed on the remedial duty roster.
你以为这就是最糟了吗
Think you can't fall any farther?
那你就错了
Think again.
他怎么样了
How is he?
没事了
He's fine.
会好起来的
Will be.
你呢
And you?
我没事
I'm good.
就几处擦伤
Few bruises.
怎么了
What?
你就是那个有名的警探吉姆・戈登  对吗
You're the famous detective Jim Gordon, aren't you?
我是叫这名  不过算不上"有名"
That's my name. I'm not sure about "Famous."
那"臭名昭著"呢
Notorious, then?
这个比较接近
Nearer the mark.
你是哪位
Who are you?
莱斯利・汤普金斯  汤普金斯医生
Leslie Thompkins. Dr. Thompkins.
你在这儿工作吗
You work here?
我又不是病人
I'm not an inmate.
以前没在医务室见过你
I haven't seen you on infirmary duty before.
我在女病患区上班
I work in the female ward.
他们缺人手了我就来帮忙
I come over here when they're short-handed.
姑娘们都在谈论你呢
All the girls are talking about you.
英勇警探对抗市政府  结果遭到打击
Brave detective brought low by fighting City Hall.
她们是这么说的吗
They say that, do they?
对不起  我不是想拿你的处境说笑
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to make light of your situation.
没事
It's okay.
我本人觉得你的行为很值得钦佩
Personally, I think what you're doing is admirable.
我在保护一群疯子
I'm guarding lunatics.
不  你是没有放弃
No. You're not quitting.
现在还没
Not yet.
你是什么人来着
Who are you?
抱歉  我不是有意说这么多的
Oh, sorry. I didn't mean to blurt all that out like I did.
不关我的事
It's none of my business.
汤普金斯医生
Uh, Dr. Thompkins,
你确定这个病人没事吗
you sure this inmate's gonna be okay?
他没事
He's fine.
药劲上来了  需要休息
He's just sleeping off his meds.
我也想休息啊
I'm trying.
你们俩开房去吧
Get a room, you guys.
我该走了
I should go.
很高兴认识你  吉姆
It's nice to meet you, Jim.
彼此彼此
Likewise.
本剧集字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译制作
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再整理而成
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留所有译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
翻译：灰灰是菇凉   艾瑞卡   DustD   Silence   charcie
翻译：爵士年代蓬蓬裙   夜影章鱼X   木浅薰   哥谭直属   草草
时间轴：讷讷   凭陵新月   宝宝
特效&后期：宝宝          校对&总监：草草
艾薇
Ivy?
你怎么样
How you doing?
我没事  挺好的
I... I'm good. I'm good.
你好像病了
You look sick.
你得去看医生了
Like you need a doctor.
不去看医生
No doctors.
再也不去看医生了
N... never, ever again.
我没事
I-I'm fine.
我在休息
I-I was resting.
我有地方能带你去  艾薇  来吧
I got a place we can go, Ivy. Come on.
我只是有点冷
I-I-I, I'm shivery is all.
好了
Okay.
来吧
Come on.
他们不在家
They're gone.
很安全
It's safe.
你确定吗
Sure?
绝对确定
Sure as sure.
我们只在这儿待到你有所好转
We'll only stay until you feel better.
去沙发上躺着
Come and lay down on the couch there.
要是主人回来了呢
What if the real people come home?
到处都是灰
There's dust on everything
还有股霉味儿
and something smells rotten.
没人会来的
Nobody's coming.
不过这是谁家
Whose place is this, anyways?
你哪来这么多问题  艾薇
How come you ask so many questions, Ivy?
我只是想帮你
I'm trying to help you.
躺下  我给你拿毯子
Now lie down and I'll get you a blanket.
早上好  先生们
Morning, gentlemen.
考虑过我的提议了吗
Have you considered my proposition?
考虑过了
Uh, yeah.
不行
No.
-不行  -我们付的够多了
- No? - We already pay enough.
马罗尼阁下去年定的税率
Don Maroni set the rates last year.
现在我要涨价了
And now I'm raising the prices.
只能怪通货膨胀
Inflation is a bitch.
马罗尼说了
Maroni said...
马罗尼  马罗尼
Maroni, Maroni....
你有点惹到我了
You're beginning to irk me.
你在跟我说话  企鹅
You're talking to me, the Penguin.
你是企鹅
So you're Penguin.
那又如何
So what?
我还向警察举报你了呢
I called the cops on you.
是企鹅大人
It's The Penguin.
还有  打电话什么的  太天真了
And that was a very naive call to make.
码头区的警察是我们的人
Hello, we own the cops on the waterfront.
跟警察说去吧  伙计
Tell that to the cops, buddy.
伙计们
Boys.
苦着脸干嘛
Why the frowns?
琼斯
Jones?
Jones.
蛙人
Frogman.
哥谭
第一季  第十一集
这是电击伤痕
These are electrode wounds.
有人对他进行了原始的侵入性的电击疗法
This man was given a crude, invasive kind of electroshock therapy.
用金属针插入大脑
Metal needles were inserted into the brain
直接对额叶进行电击
and electricity was applied to his frontal lobes.
为什么
What for?
电击手术是用来纠正异常行为的
Surgically, it's used to modify aberrant behavior,
但他被施以了太高的电压
but in this case, way too much voltage was used
他的大脑已经完全烧坏了
and his brain is completely fried.
又是在你的监管下  戈登
Another under your watch, Gordon?
这是怎么发生的
How did this happen?
你仓促开门
You rushed into opening,
现在这栋两百年的大楼
and now you're running this place
不安全  四处透风  活像迷宫
with skeleton staff and zero surveillance
人手不够  连监控都没有
in an unsafe and unsecure 200-year-old maze.
太好了  满身借口
Excellent. Excuses.
市政工程就是如此
That's that nature of municipal operations.
接手问题
You inherit problems
然后用手边有限的资源尽力而为
and you use the resources at hand to do with you can.
咱们的资源完全不够
Well, our resources don't stretch nearly far enough
展开暴力犯罪调查
to cover a criminal assault investigation.
咱们应该通知哥谭市警局
We should call the GCPD.
不  这是内部医疗问题
No, this is an in-house medical issue.
他还喘气吗
He still breathing?
是的  不过实际上他已经脑死亡了
Well, yes, but he's effectively brain dead.
那怎么...
What does...
他还能喘气
He's still breathing.
无需机器维持生命
Unaided.
那从官方角度来说
For all official purposes, well,
他还活着
he's still alive.
照顾好他  医生
Keep him comfortable, Doctor.
戈登警卫
Officer Gordon?
你去查明是哪位可爱的病友干的这事
I want you to find out which one of our charming inmates did this.
周五把报告放在我桌上
I want a report on my desk Friday.
又是个寻常的工作日
Another day, another dollar.
是吗  我倒觉得这不寻常而且很蹊跷
Really? This is rather usual and sinister, isn't it?
是啊
Yes.
我们该找什么样的人
So, who are we looking for?
做出这种事需要什么条件
What does it take to pull this off?
基础的人体解剖学知识
Some basic knowledge of human anatomy.
基础电工技能
Basic electrical skills.
电路板和几根电线
A circuit board, some wiring.
就这些
Is that all?
当然还需要门钥匙
And the door keys, of course.
门钥匙
"The door keys."
没错
Right.
没有啊  我的钥匙都在呢
No, man, I got my keys right here.
看着我  斯蒂文
Look at me, Steven.
看着我
Look at me.
告诉我实话
Tell me the truth.
你干吗针对我
Why you picking on me?
有五名警卫都有这一区的钥匙
There's five other guards with keys to this wing.
没错  但只有你一个
True, and you're the only one who looks
一副紧张兮兮的样子
and smells like a hunted animal.
斯蒂文  电了蛙人的人有钥匙
Look, Steven. Whoever fried Frogman had keys.
我们搜了所有病人的病房
Now, we've searched all the inmates' cells.
都没找到钥匙
No keys.
但是我知道钥匙被盗了
But I know they're out there.
我要查到在哪
And I need to know where.
我已经无路可走了
I'm backed up against the wall here.
而且我开始失去耐心了  你明白吗
And I'm starting to lose my patience-- do you understand?
看剧时发生的斗殴
That fight... during the play.
就在那之后  我发现我的钥匙不见了
Right after, I noticed my keys were gone.
丢钥匙可是大事
You lose equipment, that's a big deal.
会扣我一周的工钱  所以我去找了副备用的
They dock me a week's pay, so I tracked done a spare set!
谁把钥匙拿走了
Who took the keys?
我不知道
I don't know.
谁都有可能
Anyone could've taken them.
走开
Walk away.
-抱歉  -走开
- Sorry... - Walk away!
他的钱炸飞了
And then he raises our taxes
就来提我们的税
after his money blows up.
还冷血无情地杀了巴尼恩
Killed Bannion like he was nobody.
我直说了
I'll say it.
那老家伙法尔科内来找我们麻烦前
I wish something would happen to old man Falcone
但愿他能出点意外
before he comes after one of us.
我就这意思
That's where this is going.
别急  我们来想象一下
Slow down. Now, let's imagine
上帝保佑法尔科内长命百岁
God forbid anything happened to Falcone.
但只是说着玩
Just for kicks...
到时谁来接手呢
who would take over then?
谁来接手
Who would take over?
我来
I do.
你
You?
这我倒从未想过
Now, that never occurred to me.
从未想过什么
What never occurred?
论资排辈  下一个也该轮到我
I'm next in line. Seniority.
规矩就是如此
That's the way the system works.
这是以前的规矩
That's how the system used to work back in the day.
现在是个新的开端  新的城市
It's a new dawn, a new city.
我觉得我们需要新思想的人来带领我们
I would believe we would need some fresh thinking at the top.
那么你说的是哪位新思想的人呢
And who is the fresh thinker that you got in mind?
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
是谁
Who?
她呗
Her.
她指的是她自己
She's talking about her.
是嘛
Really?
你认为我无法管理整个家族吗
You don't think I could run the family?
不是  为什么不行呢
Hey, no, why not?
妇女解放什么的嘛
Woman's lib and all that.
但是公平说  下一个该轮到吉米
But fair play, Jimmy is next in line.
没必要起争执
Well, there's no need to argue.
这本来也都只是假设
It's all hypotheticals anyhow.
我们只是随便说说
We're just talking, right?
5075号病人杰克・格鲁伯
Inmate 5075 Jack Gruber.
病人格鲁伯
Inmate Gruber?
你拿了威戈警卫的钥匙吗
Did you take Officer Wenger's keys?
你在调查蛙人的不幸遭遇
You're looking into the sad demise of the Frogman.
-蛙人昨晚破坏了你的演出  -是的
- The Frogman disrupted your play last night. - Yeah.
你很讨厌他  是吧
You didn't like him very much, did you?
我对他没什么看法
Well, I had no opinion of him.
他被称作蛙人
He was called the Frogman
是因为他认为有只巨大的牛蛙寄居在他的腹中
because he believed a giant bullfrog lived inside his abdomen,
掌控着他的思想
controlling his thoughts.
他已经死了
He was already dead.
我才不把精神能量浪费在死人身上
I don't waste psychic energy on the dead.
强奸  谋杀
Rape, murder...
你惯用暴力啊  格鲁伯
You're no stranger to violence, Gruber.
你的精神评估显示你是个A类反社会者
Your psych evals say you're a grade-A sociopath.
我为什么要相信你的话
Why should I take your word for anything?
你不该对读到的东西全单照收  吉姆
You shouldn't believe everything you read, Jim.
我能叫你吉姆吗
May I call you Jim?
-是你拿的钥匙吗  -请吧
- Did you take the keys? - Please,
如果你不信任我  就去搜我病房吧
search my cell if you do not find me trustworthy,
但是  吉姆  我没有拿任何人的钥匙
but, no, Jim, I did not take anyone's keys.
谢谢你
Thank you.
警卫
Guard?
你拿了威戈警卫的钥匙吗
Did you take Officer Wenger's keys?
没有
No.
冷静
Settle down.
冷静  冷静
S-Settle down. Settle down.
你拿了警...
Did you take Off...
钥匙在你那儿
You have the keys?
拿束带  我需要束身衣
Get the straps! Need a restraint!
-钥匙  -没错
- Keys? - Yes.
钥匙  你拿警卫的钥匙了吗
Keys. Did you take the guard's keys?
没有  我惹麻烦了吗
No. Am I in trouble?
没有  艾伦
No, Aaron,
除非你在撒谎
unless you're lying to me.
撒谎
Lying?
艾伦从不撒谎  戈登先生
Aaron never lies, Mr. Gordon.
他没有这个概念
He doesn't have the concept,
真是个可怜的家伙
poor peaceful soul that he is.
他拿斧子杀了他全家
He killed his family with an axe.
是这样吗  艾伦
Isn't that what you did, Aaron?
除此之外连只苍蝇都没伤害过
Never harmed a fly before or since.
我道过歉了
I said sorry.
艾伦
Okay, Aaron.
你可以走了
You're free to go.
谢谢你  警卫
Thank you. Guard?
看到了吧
You saw how that went.
问题在于萨维亚诺
Saviano's the problem.
亚纳切克如果落单  我就能搞定
Now, on his own, Janacek, I can turn him around.
小混混就都跟着去了
And the junior capos will follow him.
但是萨维亚诺
But that Saviano,
咱们得在出击马罗尼之前就搞定他
we got to deal with him before we make our move on Maroni.
不如让我跟萨维亚诺谈谈
Why not let me talk to Saviano on my own?
我和吉米是老交情了
Me and Jimmy go way back.
的确  你俩是老交情了
That's true. You do go way back.
你会跟他说什么
What would you tell him?
我会说你是最好的人选
I'd say you're the best candidate.
他也知道
He knows that.
只是不愿当面承认
He just can't admit it to your face.
太骄傲了
Too proud.
那好
Okay then.
去跟他谈
Talk to him.
没问题
Will do.
布奇
Butch,
你没打算背叛我吧
you're not turning on me, are you?
这算什么意思
What kind of question is that?
你怎么能开这种玩笑
Why would you even joke about something like that?
问问而已
I'm just asking.
女人家有时就是没安全感
A girl gets insecure once in a while.
罗伊斯顿  你在这儿干吗呢
Royston, what are you doing out of your cell?
够了
Hey, cut it out!
五寻的水深处躺着你的父亲
Full fathom five thy father lies.
他的骨骼已化成珊瑚
Of his bones are coral made.
见鬼
Aw, hell.
你是叫罗伊斯顿吗
Royston, is that your name?
海的女神时时摇起他的丧钟
Sea-nymphs hourly ring his knell.
好精彩
Fascinating.
他能走能说
The poor man can walk and talk,
但只记得剧本里的台词
but all he remembers are lines from the play.
用的是跟蛙人相同的电击疗法
Same electroshock technique as Frogman
但结果较温和
but with slightly less drastic results.
看来不管是谁做的  那人在改进方法
It's like whoever's doing this is improving their methods.
或许那人毫无计划
Or maybe their process is so haphazard,
自己都不知道会是什么结果
they don't know what kind of outcome they're gonna get.
一个成了植物人
One man ends up a vegetable,
另一个反复背诵莎士比亚
while the other one recites Shakespeare on a loop.
真不明白病人这么折磨病人
I don't understand what an inmate gains
能有什么好处
from scrambling up another inmate.
这段时间你最好留在女病患区那边
You should stay on the female wing for a while.
你没必要让自己涉险
There's no reason to put yourself in danger.
我能照顾好自己
I'm perfectly capable of protecting myself.
再说  病人也需要我
Besides, my patients need me.
这边可能要出大乱子
There's gonna be some drama around here.
钥匙丢失引导我去查病人
The missing keys made me focus on the inmates,
但我觉得这是个误导
but I think it's a misdirection.
我觉得应该排查员工
I think I should be focusing on the staff.
我明白了
I see.
那还真是要出乱子了
There will be some drama.
不过等等  我也是员工啊
But, wait, I'm staff.
说不定就是我呢
What if it's me?
-不是你  -你怎么知道
- It's not you. - How can you tell?
-你不是那种人  -警察的绝招吗
- You're not the type. - Cop skills, huh?
会读人
You can read people.
一部分人而已
Some people.
是员工  太荒唐了
A staff member? That's absurd.
-是病人干的  -我觉得不是
- It was an inmate. - I don't think so.
你的工作是监督病人的安全
Your job is to oversee inmate security.
你无权对员工进行调查
You're not authorized to conduct an investigation of the staff.
你是想向我施压
You're trying to force my hand.
你想逼我报警
You want me to call the police.
不是
No.
我已经报了
I already called 'em.
芭芭拉  起床了
Barbara, you need to wake up.
早上好
Morning.
我给你买了咖啡
I got you coffee.
加糖特甜
Mmm, extra sweet.
你一直记得
You always remember.
是啊
Yeah.
联系吉姆了吗
Have you spoken to Jim recently?
为什么要联系他
Why would I?
芮妮  你不需要吃吉姆的醋
Renee, you don't have to be jealous of Jim.
我不爱他了
I'm over him.
这是个错误
This was a mistake.
什么是错误
What was?
我们
This. Us.
我不该放任我们发展到这一步
I should have never let it go on for this long.
对不起
I'm s... I'm sorry.
我明白了
Oh, I-I see.
听我说  芭芭拉
Look, Barbara...
不用说了  我明白...
No. No. I mean, you're...
你说的一点没错  这是个错误
No, you are absolutely right. This-this was a mistake.
我已经戒瘾很久了
This has been a really long process for me,
我一直努力使自己重回正轨
and I've worked too hard to get right with myself.
我希望我们能重归于好  但我不能重蹈覆辙
I-I wanted this to be good, but I can't fall back now.
酗酒  嗑药
The drinking, the drugs.
我们在互相毒害
We're toxic together, you and me.
求你了  芮妮  别说了
Please, Renee, stop.
一个字都不必多说了
There's no need to say another word.
对不起  我影响了你的戒瘾
I am sorry that I interfered with your process.
芭芭拉  你需要帮助
Barbara, you need help
但我帮不了你
I can't give you right now.
-我帮你打给吉姆吧  -不
- Let me call Jim for you, please. - No.
我的钱包呢
Where's my purse?
你不必走  留下
You don't need to go. Stay here.
给自己一点恢复的时间  我走
Take time to get yourself together. I'll go.
我现在就很好  多谢劳神
I am perfectly together, thank you.
我不就是害人的毒药嘛
I am just toxic, that's all.
该死的钱包到底在哪
Now, where's my damn purse?!
芭芭拉  别这样
Barbara, stop.
请你冷静一点
Calm down, please, all right?
我走
I'll go.
求你了
Please.
好吧
Fine.
随你吧  走
Do what you want. Go.
-对不起  -走吧
- I'm sorry... - Just go.
你好  哥们
Hey, pal.
在一朵莲香花的冠中我躺着休息
In a cow slip's bell I lie,
我安然睡去  当夜枭开始它的呜咽
there I crouch when owls do cry.
挺好
All right.
挺美的
I can dig that.
-警探  -吉姆
- Detective... - Jim!
老搭档  亲一个
Partner. Mwah!
让我好好看看你
Let me take a good look at you.
老天保佑  当警卫了
Lord have mercy, a screw.
-你怎么回事  -边儿去没空理你
- Excuse me. - Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
你还真没唬人啊
Hey, you weren't exaggerating.
跟你说的一样诡异
Freaky as advertised.
我没让任何人叫你来  先生
Nobody of authority called on you, sir.
这不是警察的事
This is not a police matter.
想必你就是院长朗医生
You must be Director Dr. Lang.
我就不同意你的话
See, I beg to differ.
这最起码是一起三级袭击案件
This is third degree assault, at the very least.
这是你哥们吧
A friend of yours, is it?
你这是极其严重的抗命行为
Egregious insubordination.
你的饭碗已经岌岌可危了
Your job here was already hanging on a thread.
你的执法生涯就到此为止了
This is the end of your career in law enforcement.
等着瞧吧
Count on it.
你悠着点  大哥
Take it easy, hot shot.
戈登警卫的做法是正确的
Officer Gordon did the right thing.
为什么他不能叫警察
Why wouldn't he call the police?
没准别人会以为你不希望把事情搞大呢
Anyone would think you'd want to keep this business quiet.
杰瑞  你是叫杰瑞是吧
Gerry... it is Gerry, isn't it?
我问你  这是你做的好事吗  杰瑞
Now, did you do this terrible thing, Gerry?
这问题简直不值得回答
That doesn't even merit a reply.
不  这不是我做的好事
No, I did not do this terrible thing.
但你是医生  你有这个技术
But you have the skill, though, as a doctor.
你肯定能做得干净利落
I mean, you could do it, lickety-split.
我为什么要这么做
Now, why would I do this?
别人又是为什么呢
Why would anyone?
说得好  戈登警卫
Exactly, Officer Gordon.
杰瑞  恐怕我得请你去局里走一趟了
Gerry, I think we're gonna have to take you down to the precinct
你身上的嫌疑实在太大
you're raising a lot of questions
必须得正式讯问清楚才行
that need clearing up in a more formal setting.
-你不能强迫我去  -闭嘴
- Well, you can't do this... - Sh-Sh-Sh-Shush.
从此刻起  哥谭市警局正式接手调查此案
As of this moment, this is an official GCPD investigation.
你要是不配合  就等着被捕吧
You, sir, will cooperate or face arrest.
戈登警卫
Officer Gordon?
能不能麻烦你过一遍工作人员档案
Would you mind going through the, uh, staff records
我要带这位杰瑞去喝杯茶了
while I take Gerry, here, downtown for a chat?
遵命  警探
Will do, Detective.
走吧
Sir?
吉米
Jimmy.
布奇
Butch.
见到你很高兴
Good to see you.
来
Come on.
就跟过去一样  是吧
Like old times, huh?
就差来一瓶苹果白兰地了
All we need is a bottle of applejack.
人生无常啊  兄弟
What happened, man?
在我心里  我们
In my head, it's...
-还是在哈洛公园追妹子的小青年  -是啊
- we're still kids, chasing girls in Harlow Park. - Yeah.
还真追着几个挺靓的  是吧
We caught a couple of hot ones, huh?
尤其是我
Especially me.
多谢你来见我
Thanks for meeting with me.
你怎么跟你家大姐大说的
What did you tell your boss-lady?
我提议约你出来谈谈  她同意了
I suggested I reach out to you. She agreed.
做我工作吗
Talk some sense into me?
说什么新开端
It's a new dawn.
差不多吧
Yeah, like that.
她说得倒没错
She's not wrong, you know?
市里局势变了
City's changing.
你真想接法尔科内的班
You really want Falcone's job?
我从小就把你当亲兄弟看待
Since we were kids, I love you like a brother.
我也是
I love you, too.
永远不变  你知道的
Always. You know that.
我知道
I do, I do.
所以我才信任你
That's why I trust you.
我现在说这话是出于对你的爱
And that's why I say to you with love...
菲什没戏了
Fish is doomed.
她接不了大位的  不可能
There's no way she gets the chair. It ain't gonna happen.
她是个聪明人  但她太不自量力
She's a smart cookie, but she's overreaching.
老实说  布奇
I mean, come on, Butch,
除了你和你的人  她还有什么
without you and your crew, what's she got?
没什么了
Very little.
这谁都明白  你也是
Everybody knows it. You know it.
也许吧
Maybe.
你需要什么条件才愿意动手
What's it gonna take to make you make a move?
你能出什么价
What are you offering?
随你开
Name it.
离开菲什  投靠我们
Drop Fish, come over to us.
俱乐部  和相关的生意  都是你的了
The club-- all the businesses attached-- they're yours.
这还只是开始  作为签约奖金
That's day one. A welcome bonus.
你还想要什么
What else you want?
问的好
That's a good question.
让我考虑一下吧
Let me think it over.
当然
Yeah.
兄弟
Hey, brother.
可别想太久
Don't think too long, huh?
布洛克警探
Detective Bullock.
等会儿
Wait here.
企鹅
Penguin.
真高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
过得怎么样啊
What are you guys doing?
老朋友
Old friend.
感谢上帝你来了
Thank goodness you're here.
这完全是出了点小误会
There's been some silly mistake.
一看就是
Looks like it.
除非你真惹恼了什么大人物
Unless you irritated someone important--
你没有吧
you didn't do that, did you?
我
Me?
当然没有
Of course not.
你确定吗
You sure?
好好扪心自问一下  企鹅
Examine your soul, Penguin.
等等
Wait!
别走  求你  先生  我求你
Don't go. Please, sir, I-I beg of you.
我家老大  马罗尼阁下
My patron, Don Maroni,
显然还不知道我的窘况
is obviously unaware of my predicament.
只要打个电话  问题肯定就能解决
A simple phone call would resolve things, I'm sure.
但是你看  我喜欢看你待在这儿
But, see, I like having you here.
这样我就可以悠闲地坐在办公桌边
'Cause I can sit at my desk
看着你
and look at you.
这让人心情愉快
It's soothing.
就像看一株盆栽
Like a bonsai tree.
盆栽是什么
What's a bonsai tree?
那么
So...
你见到我们的朋友了吗
did you see our friend?
见了
I saw him.
然后呢
And?
我还在劝他
I'm working him.
他挺固执的
He's a stubborn cuss, that one.
给他点时间吧
Just give him a little time.
时间啊
Time, hmm?
好啊
Okay.
可以给他时间
He can have time.
好
Yeah.
我很有信心
I'm optimistic.
很好
Good.
好吧  医生
All right, Doctor,
假装我什么都不知道
pretend I'm an ignoramus.
这应该不会太难想象吧
Shouldn't be too hard, hmm?
向我解释一下这个疯狂的电针疗法
Explain to me this whole crazy electric needle business.
像你这样真医生这么做时
When a real doctor like you does it,
会有什么效果
what's it supposed to do?
电击疗法是改变情绪和行为的
Electroshock therapy is a common procedure
普通手术
for mood and behavior alteration.
-像是精神控制  -差不多
- Like mind control? - Of a sort.
对人类进行蓝天实验
Blue sky experimentation on humans
被认为是不道德的
is considered unethical,
所以我们对其硬科学知之甚少
so we know very little of the hard science.
好吧
Okay.
不过熟练的外科医生能够引起特定的反应
But skilled surgeons can elicit very specific responses.
但治疗那些病人的并非熟练的外科医生
But those inmates weren't treated by a skilled surgeon.
你确定吗
You sure about that?
病人中没有熟练的外科医生
There are no skilled surgeons amongst the inmates.
员工中也没有
Or the staff.
但你是个熟练的外科医生
You're a skilled surgeon.
搞什么...我们讨论过这个了
What... We've been over this.
我从医学院毕业后就没给人开过刀了
I haven't opened a body since med school.
我跟你开玩笑呢
I'm just messing with you.
我不认为你是幕后黑手
I don't think you're the man behind this.
你不是破坏规矩的那种人
No, you're not the type to break rules.
太过害怕权威
Too scared of authority.
但是你有所隐瞒  是什么
But you're hiding something. What is it?
人人都有秘密
Well, everybody's hiding something.
别耍我
Don't play tag.
你说得对  警探
You're right, Detective.
我是害怕权威
I am afraid of authority.
而我所隐瞒的事
And the things I'm hiding?
我绝不会告诉你
I'll never tell you.
-听上去很重大  -重大
- Sounds heavy. - Heavy?
是的  你要是知道分寸
Yes. And if you know what's good for you,
就不会再去深挖
you won't dig any deeper.
好吧
All right.
我可不想触霉头
I don't want to hit any power lines.
这不用你说
Don't have to tell me twice.
不深挖  当然  除非
No digging. Unless, of course,
这和手头这桩案子有关
it has something to do with the case at hand.
毫无关联
Nothing.
太棒了  谢谢你
Oh. Great, thank you.
小可怜  你脸色好苍白
Oh, you poor thing. You look so pale.
找到什么了吗
Any joy?
还没有
Not so far.
档案貌似不完整
The files seem to be incomplete.
不知道地下室里还有没有别的
I'm wondering if there's more in the basement.
蓝图上说下面有个档案室
Blueprint says there's a records office down there.
地下室关闭了
Oh, the basement's closed off.
有危险化学物质
Unsafe chemicals.
已经十年没人下去过了
Nobody's been down there for ten years.
你知道怎么下去吗
Do you know the way down there?
假设你必须挑出你的一个员工
All right, suppose you had to pick out one member of your staff
作为犯人  你会选谁
as the culprit. Who would it be?
不是员工干的
It wasn't a staff member.
管他呢  你首先想到的那个人是谁
Whatever. Just the first face that pops to your mind.
没有人
Nobody.
他们都是好人  我了解他们
They're good people. I know them well.
他们都跟我干了五年多了
They've all been with me for more than five years.
我们是一起来到阿卡姆的
We all came to Arkham together.
等等
Wait.
就这个  你刚刚想到了一个人  是谁
Hold that. You just saw someone. Who was it?
不  她不可能...
Oh. No, she couldn't...
女的
She?
谁
Who?
什么声音
What's that?
大家都在病房里
Everybody's in their cell.
桃乐西
Dorothy.
吉姆  你好啊
Jim, hi. What's up?
莱斯利
Hi, Leslie.
我们要去地下室历险
We're going on an adventure to the basement.
听上去很好玩啊
Oh. Well, that sounds fun.
-我一起来吧  -不行
- Can I come? - No.
-但是...  -汤普金斯医生
- But... - Dr. Thompkins,
我之前怎么说的
what did I tell you earlier?
你回家吧
You should go home.
怎么了  出什么事了
Why? What's wrong?
没出什么事
Nothing's wrong.
回家吧
Go home.
我不明白...
I don't understa...
没事吧
You okay?
-没事  -好
- I-I'm fine. - Okay.
去找正门的警卫
I need you to find the main entry guard,
叫他封锁整栋大楼
tell him to hit lockdown,
-然后马上离开这里  -好
- then get out of the building, quick. - Okay,
封锁大楼  然后出去  没问题
hit lockdown. Get out. Will do.
喂
Yeah.
吉姆  听我说
Jim, listen,
桃乐西・邓肯不是员工  她是病人
Dorothy Duncan isn't staff. She's an inmate.
我知道  赶紧过来
I know. Get over here now.
警告  限制区域
莱斯利
Leslie!
警卫
Guard!
警卫  救命
Guard! Help!
汤普金斯医生
Dr. Thompkins.
吉姆  小心身后
Jim, behind you.
喂
Men!
你们干什么呢
Men! What the hell do you think you're playing at?!
给我回病房去
Go back in your cells
马上
right now!
听到了吗
You hear me?
这是命令
That's an order!
记住  我食素  别加黄油
Remember, I'm a vegan-- no butter.
知道啦
Yeah, yeah.
这是...
I-Is this...
吉姆・戈登在吗
Is Jim Gordon there?
他在
Yes, he is.
不过抱歉  吉姆现在正忙呢
But I'm sorry, Jim is kind of busy right now.
有话要转达吗
Can I take a message?
不用了
No.
算了
No, that's okay.
我...
I...
你是哪位
Who is this?
我是吉姆的朋友
I'm a friend of Jim's.
你是谁
Who's that?
去死吧
Go to hell!
法医在停尸房验尸呢
M.E.'s got her in the morgue.
桃乐西・邓肯16岁在护士学院时
When Dorothy Duncan was a 16-year-old nursing student,
用有毒的糖果杀了5个孩子
she killed five kids with poison candy--
她说这是做功课
for homework, she said.
她半辈子都待在阿卡姆
She's spent over half her life at Arkham.
疯人院关闭的时候  乱成一团
When the asylum closed, there was chaos.
她一定是一直躲在地下室里
She must have just hunkered down in the basement
一直待到重开
until it reopened.
鉴证组在检查地下室呢
Forensics is sweeping the basement level
寻找她的藏身处
looking for her lair.
可怜人
Poor soul.
她究竟是想干什么啊
What was she trying to do?
谁知道呢
Who knows?
或许她只是想找到医治自己病症的办法
Maybe she was just trying to find a cure for her own madness.
她是个疯子  这就够了
She was crazy. Enough said.
见到你真好  吉姆
It's good to see you, Jim.
而且你立了功
And you got a win, huh?
还在为正义而战  真不错
Still fightin'. Nice work.
我上司估计不会这么想
Yeah, I don't think my boss is gonna see it that way.
他老板特别不好伺候
He's working for the king of all cheese grinders.
这太可惜了  警监  我们得把他弄回来
It's a crying shame, Cap-- we need to get him back on the job.
你知道我也非常想把你弄回来  可惜做不到
You know I'd bring you back here in a second... if I could.
我知道
I know.
没事  警监
It's all good, Captain.
你穿这身制服还挺像样
You do look spiffy in the uniform.
像傻样吧
Yeah, if spiffy means dorky.
谢你全家了
Thank you. Thank you very much.
看在过去的分上  喝杯酒吧
How about a drink for old times' sake?
好啊
Sounds good.
企鹅
Penguin.
先生
Sir.
马罗尼阁下
Don Maroni.
您总算来了
Thank heavens you're here.
你脏兮兮的
You look kind of frowsty.
抱歉
Forgive me.
从昨天早上到现在就只有张湿巾能擦擦
I've had nothing but a moist towelette since yesterday morning.
真是惨啊
A very sad picture.
你知道你为什么关在里面吗
You know why you're in there?
不知道
I have no idea.
这是反问
A rhetorical question.
你关在这儿  是我的意思
You're in there because I put you in there.
但是  马罗尼阁下  为什么啊
But, Don Maroni, wh-why?
我做了什么
What did I do?
你知道什么是自大吗
Do you know what hubris is?
知道吗
Do you know?!
抱歉
Sorry.
我以为这也是...
I-I thought that was another...
反问...
rhetorical...
呢...
question.
是的  我知道  自大就是...
Yes, I do. H-Hubris. It's when...
就是没多少斤两的小跛子
It's when limping little chickenbutt second bananas
当自己是个人物
think they're hot stuff.
-先生  -傻了吧唧的下人
- Sir... - When dumbass underlings
不问我就去提税
raise taxes without asking me first.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
还是渔民  你提渔民的税
On fishermen. You raised taxes on fishermen.
他们在大海里
They're out there in the freakin' ocean
为我们拿命冒险
risking their lives for us,
你敢不问我就去提他们的税
and you raise their taxes without asking me?
这就是自大  我的朋友
That's hubris, my friend.
对不起  马罗尼阁下
I'm sorry, Don Maroni.
非常抱歉
Deeply... sorry.
再不会犯了
I will never do it again.
好吧
All right, then.
你
Hey, you.
把我朋友放出来
Let my friends out.
-什么  -我说外语了吗
- Excuse me? - What, am I talking Hungarian?
给我开牢门
Open the cage, mook.
过来
Come here.
老天啊  你臭死了
Holy Mother, you stink!
这就算是教训了
Let this be a lesson to you, yes?
是  先生
Yes, sir.
你是只聪明的小猴子
You're a smart monkey...
但你始终是个猴子
but you're a monkey.
我是动物园的看守
And I'm the zookeeper.
没事了
Yeah, you're all right.
警监  你得看看这个
Captain, you should see this.
看
Look here.
桃乐西・邓肯  电灼伤  两边都有
Dorothy Duncan. Electrode wounds, both sides.
跟其他人受害人伤口尺寸一样
Same gauge as the other victims.
有一个月了  被头发挡着
About a month old. They were hidden by her hair.
这怎么会呢  她怎么能自己电自己
This is crazy-- how could she have done this to herself?
她不能
She couldn't.
这是人做不到的
Not humanly possible.
那么她也是个受害人
Which means she was just another victim.
她不是凶手
She couldn't.
该死
Aw, crap.
艾伦
Hey, Aaron.
什么事
What's up?
你哪来的钥匙
Where'd you get those...
好样的  艾伦
Well done, Aaron.
就像我嘱咐的那样
Exactly like I told you.
你是我目前最棒的作品
Oh, now you are my best work so far.
你好  朗医生
Hello, Dr. Lang.
朗
Lang?
Lang!
他们跑了
They're gone.
去叫救护车
Get an ambulance. Go.
不是
Not...
员工
staff.
别说话  呼吸  保持呼吸
Don't speak. Just breathe. Breathe!
格鲁伯
Gr... Gruber.
亲爱的戈登警卫
Dear Officer Gordon,
抱歉  我不得不逃走
sorry I had to run.
我走之前
I very much wanted to enjoy
真想好好跟你聊聊
a proper chat with you before I left, but...
但演艺圈就是如此
that's show business.
我在这些可怜人身上锻炼技艺有段时间了
I've been practicing my skills on these sad creatures for a while now.
电真是了不起
Electricity is an amazing thing.
能创造奇迹
It can work wonders.
桃乐西护士就是早期的成功案例
Nurse Dorothy was an early success.
最后这次  我想我终于做对了
This last time, I think I finally got one just right.
我真是不错
Bravo to me.
但我该走了
But time to go.
认识你很高兴  吉姆
It was nice to meet you... Jim,
希望还能再见
and I hope to see you around.
祝你顺利  杰克・格鲁伯
All the best, Jack Gruber.
芭芭拉
Barbara?
你怎么样
How you doing?
挺好  你呢
Well. You?
挺好的  一向如此
Tip-top. Always.
怎么样  兄弟  你加入吗
So, what's the deal, brother, are you in?
嗯
Yeah.
我加入
I'm in.
这就对了
That's my boy!
说条件吧
Name your terms.
记得我们14的时候
You remember when we were 14,
去萨特利安尼的店里偷肉
we stole all that meat from Satriani's?
嗯  记得  偷了50磅的猪肉什么的
Yeah, I do. It was, like, 50 pounds of pork and whatnot.
我妈妈乐坏了
Never seen my mom so happy.
是啊
Yeah.
问题是  我分东西的时候
Thing is, when I was sharing it out,
有15磅上好的安格斯牛排
there was, like, 15 pounds of prime angus beefsteaks in there.
都被我扣下了
And I kept it all for myself.
一点没给你
I didn't give you any.
给你的都是便宜货
Gave you all the cheap cuts.
我完全不知道呢
I never knew that.
嗯  这事一直困扰我
Yeah, it's been bugging me ever since.
这都很久以前了
Hey, we're talking a long time ago.
我想说声对不起
I want to say I'm sorry.
抱歉我扣了该给你的牛排
I apologize for cheating you out of your beefsteak.
别提了
Forget about it.
不行
Nah. Nah.
好兄弟不该做这种事
Brothers don't do that.
我为什么那么做啊
Why did I do that?
别去想了  没事的
Forget about it-- it's okay.
我接受你的道歉了
Apology accepted.
谢谢
Thank you.
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com